Codex's new ultrafast is really fast.
Here I just asked what did I talk about
in this week's community Q&A call and
you can see how fast it's going to go
find the right call, get the transcript
and summarize that up. This was a
54minute call that it had to look
through and give me a summary of and it
did that in 20 seconds or sorry 19
seconds. So ultraast is only available
with GBD6 Astra and you can see we had
standard fast but now we have ultraast.
Now the thing about ultraast is it's
only available on their new plan they
just announced which is $500 a month.
Here you can see the fastest work and
codecs. This isn't available on $200 a
month or $100 a month. Now, what
actually is ultraast? It's the fastest
way to build with Astra in codecs. It's
eight times faster than standard and
four times faster than the regular fast
mode. So, obviously today I'm going to
show you guys a few examples of me
running ultra fast versus standard. And
we'll compare the quality of the outputs
as well as how much it ate of my weekly
usage. It basically just moves a lot
faster up to 300 tokens per second,
which is really, really fast. That's
faster than any human could read. But
like I said, it's on the 500 bucks plan
or on the API and it's also going to be
coming to GBD 6.1 Soul soon, which is
great because Soul is also a lot
cheaper. So hopefully the Ultra Fast
won't eat as much of my usage because
this thing eats usage. Okay, so here's a
first example that I want to show you
guys. I asked Astra to create me a
60-second showre from my recent trip to
Google in San Jose. I gave it two files
and these two files combined was 11
minutes of me kind of talking about my
experience, reflecting on it. And then I
gave it a folder with these raw assets.
And this folder contains over 145
gigabytes of footage to actually comb
through and try to tell a story out of.
And I told it to do this in a 9 by6
format. So something that could go on
Instagram or Tik Tok or, you know, a
YouTube short. Now, before we watch the
outputs, let me show you guys the stats
right here. When we did this Google
video, I did both of these on extra
high. So extra high reasoning, and we
did one with standard, one with
ultraast. And here are the stats.
Ultraast ran in about 19 minutes and
cost 17% of my weekly usage, which is
absurd. This is the weekly usage of the
$500 a month pro plan and standard ran
for 50 minutes and cost 4% of my weekly
usage. So, we'll dive a little bit more
into that, but first let's actually go
ahead and watch the outputs. I'm first
going to play the standard output and
then I'm going to play the ultraast
output and you guys let me know which
one you thought was actually better.
Like, man, this energy here is really,
really cool. So, the Google campus that
we were actually touring here, it was in
San Jose. So, it felt like a college
campus. Great energy. There were these
Gbikes all over that people were riding
around between buildings. You kind of
got inside these modern looking
buildings and there was so much
character. There was so much color
everywhere. That's where we did like the
soccer ball test. Yeah, kicking the
soccer ball with all of those Google
pixels up on the walls to analyze. It
gave you these custom cards. We talked a
lot about how much quicker we're all
able to move now, which is pretty cool.
We the humans have to be in control with
things like judgment and clear
boundaries, clear definitions of done
and just a clear goal. It's all about
how do you find what you're good at and
what you're passionate about and find
out how in that domain AI makes you a
superhuman. It [music] makes you faster.
It allows you to do more in less time.
Thank you guys so much. I appreciate it.
It was super fun. hope that we get to
come back and do it again sometime.
Man, this energy here is really, really
cool.
But that is one thing I appreciated
about Google is that you kind of got
inside these modern looking buildings
and there was so much character. There
was just so much color everywhere
[music] and everyone I talked to there
loved what they did and they loved the
culture which I thought was really cool.
And then we got to see all these other
ways that Google AI is being used in
things like retail and inventory and all
these different little demos.
>> But we talked about how much these AI
skills are going to matter even for
people that don't think they're going to
be in a techf facing role.
It's all about how do you find what
you're good at and what you're
passionate about and find out how in
that domain AI makes you a superhum.
>> [music]
>> Huge shout out to Google for having us
out. Hope that we get to come back and
do it again sometime.
So, I definitely thought that the
ultraast output was better. It felt more
Google branded. It just felt like it
told a better story. You'll also notice
it was kind of annoying in the standard
version. It was kind of like cutting off
what I was saying before my sentence
actually finished. So, it just didn't
feel very natural. I was actually very
impressed by how it was able to comb
through all this stuff and actually make
a story out of it. I mean, this is a lot
of B-roll and a lot of stuff to sort of
pull together, but I like the story that
it told here. And that was interesting
to me because you kind of would assume,
okay, it's the same model. It's the same
reasoning effort. They're probably going
to have a similar type of output, but it
doesn't feel similar at all. It even
feels like for this one, I didn't even
use Astra. It felt like I kind of maybe
I used GBD6 Soul or something like that.
Like it felt like a different model, a
worse model, even though it ran for a
lot longer. But this is interesting
because in this case, ultra fast was
about, you know, 2.5x faster than
standard. So, not the kind of marketed
8x faster, but I would never really care
about the speed if it was going to eat
that much more of my weekly usage.
That's, you know, 4x more, 4.25x more of
my usage. I would not really be going
for that. Anyways, that was kind of a
complex use case. This one's a little
bit more, I would say, normal or maybe
something I would do more frequently,
where I'm asking it to create a YouTube
resource guide from a YouTube video,
which was the one I just did with Open
Eyes Dots versus Meta's Muse. And I did
this once again, same exact prompt with
standard and ultraast. And you can see
here, standard took 13 minutes and
ultraast took 1 minute and 43 seconds.
So, this is actually closer to that 8x
speed that was marketed. It's still a
little bit less. This was more around
seven, but still, this one was
definitely much faster. And it was only
a little bit more on the usage. So 3%
more than 1%. So it feels like to me
after a couple prompts that I've been
testing, you know, difference between
standard and ultra fast, it is
definitely faster. There's no doubt
about it. And I would probably use it if
I'm in a pinch and I need to do
something actually fast, maybe 5 minutes
before a meeting or something like that.
Because when you do these smaller tasks
that maybe don't require so much input
and so much thinking and back and forth
and verification, then you know you're
probably going to be in a situation
where the amount of usage that you're
actually increasing is maybe two to 4x.
But of course, as that multiple scales
up, it's going to just eat more and
more. And normally when I'm working in
codeex or cloud code, I don't really
need things to happen that fast,
especially as they get more complex. I
like to iterate. I like to, you know,
let it run. I don't really care about
speed. But if you do, then obviously
it's really nice to have this ultra fast
lever that you can pull. Just be aware
that you're going to be paying a lot
more for it. But that is ultimately how
the world works. So it makes perfect
sense. But let's actually go look at
these two outputs real quick. Okay, so
here are the two resource guides. I'm
not going to yet say which one's which
because I want you to think like is one
of these noticeably better and worth the
money that we paid for it or not really.
So OpenAI Dots versus Muse. They both
have a link up here at the top. This one
has a longer kind of like summary up
top. We have number one, what these
personal agents do. They both link to
the YouTube video up at the top. As you
can see, we've got a scope. We've got a
decision rule. Number two is memory,
context, and personalization. Memory and
personal context. Number three is
communication and ecosystem. Number
three over here is channels and
ecosystem. So ultimately, you guys can
see that these are very, very similar.
They're similarly branded because they
both use the same skill and they have
similar structure. Number six is dots,
strengths, friction, and verdict. Over
here is working inside of dots. And then
we get over here to some key takeaways
and we have the end of the doc. And they
both link back to AIS+ at the bottom.
These both ended up being seven pages.
As you can see, the key takeaways is
longer over here. But the one on the
right also has these useful links which
is the YouTube video as well as getting
started with dots from OpenAI and a doc
from introducing Muse. Do we have any
other links on this left-hand side? I
don't see any other links besides just
the actual YouTube video it looks like.
So anyways, this one on the left, this
one was the ultra fast, and this one on
the right was the standard. So
obviously, I don't think one is
meaningfully better than the other. And
I think that's a really good argument to
say maybe even this one was a little bit
better. But ultimately, they're both
about, you know, 9 out of 10 or
whatever. But I wouldn't care to wait 13
minutes and use 1% for an output that's
pretty much just the same as me waiting
2 minutes and using 3% of my usage. And
ultimately guys, I do use fast mode a
lot, 1.5 speed, and I don't really
notice too much of it using a crazy
amount of usage. Obviously, it does use
more than if you just use it on
standard, but I like to use fast a lot.
And then I also like to use fast when
I'm on like 6.1 soul and things like
that as well. So, if you're constantly
hitting your usage, then yeah, it's
probably worth getting up to the $500 a
month plan and then maybe playing around
with ultraast and just knowing, okay,
cool. I have that lever if I need to
pull it. But ultimately, I will probably
never be using ultra fast unless I
really, really need, you know, my back's
up against the wall for some reason. But
then I would argue that maybe you should
be building other systems to help you
not get in a situation where you're in a
time crunch rather than having to pull
that as like the last resort. But
anyways, I know this one was super
quick, but just wanted to show you guys
real quick what that actually looked
like. Hopefully, you enjoyed, you
learned something new, and if you did,
please give it a like. It helps me out a
ton. And as always, I appreciate you
guys making it to the end of the video,
and I'll see you all in the next one.
Thanks everyone.